<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Janesh Devkota&#39;s Garden</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Janesh Devkota&#39;s Garden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting water quality data from DataRetrieval Package</title>
      <link>/2018/02/extracting-water-quality-data-from-dataretrieval-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/extracting-water-quality-data-from-dataretrieval-package/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I will be showing some capabilities of dataRetrieval package by USGS to extract water quality data.
To install the dataRetrieval package use the following command:
devtools::install_github(repo = &amp;quot;USGS-R/dataRetrieval&amp;quot;) The main function I will be discussing is readWQPdata. The users can search the data using various options as shown below:
 bBox = Bounding box that uses the coordinates of lower left corner and upper right corner lat / long = lat / long will be specified by the user if they are interested to see if any data is available within radial distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial data and coordinate transformation in R</title>
      <link>/2017/12/spatial-analysis-and-coordinate-transformation-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/spatial-analysis-and-coordinate-transformation-in-r/</guid>
      <description>I come to these situations where I have to work with spatial datasets frequently. Sometimes the datasets is in lat-long format and sometimes on UTM (Universal transverse Mercator) coordinate or state plane coordinate system.
I extensively use EFDC (Environmental Fluid Dynamic Code) model to do environmental modeling and have to convert the data into UTM coordinate system. I had used CORPSCON in the past but as an R enthusiast I wanted to dig deeper in R and finad a way to do the transformation in R environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Earthquake in Nepal : Earthquake magnitude and Casualty Analysis</title>
      <link>/2017/12/2015-earthquake-in-nepal-data-analysis-and-implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/2015-earthquake-in-nepal-data-analysis-and-implications/</guid>
      <description>In this blogpost, I am going to take the earthquake data from April 2015 to May 2016 throughout the World. Then we will process the data in usable form and look at the data on Nepal. Later, we will also dive into the casualties from this devastating earthquake. We will look at how many people died, got injured from which district, using ggplot2, wordcloud and leaflet package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Janesh Devkota, PhD</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Business Intelligence Engineer working in Amazon. I work on machine learning, data analysis, visualization and use R and python extensively.
Before Amazon, I worked as a water resources / environmental engineer currently working in Dynamic Solutions International LLC in Edmonds, WA. I completed my PhD from Auburn University in 2014 and completed masters in Civil Engineering (MCE) from Auburn University in Summer 2012. During my PhD in Auburn, I worked on number of projects that required numerical modeling, data analysis, data munging, data visualization and machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications / Presentations / Project Experience</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications  Devkota, J., Fang, X., and Fang, V. Z. (2013). “Response characteristics of Perdido and Wolf Bay system to inflows and sea level rise.” British Journal of Environment and Climate Change, 3(2), 229-256. Devkota, J., and Fang, X. (2014). “Numerical simulation of flow dynamics in a tidal river under various upstream hydrologic conditions.” Hydrological Sciences Journal, 1-24. Devkota, J., and Fang, X. (2015). “Quantification of Water and Salt Exchanges in a Tidal Estuary.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>